Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
It is the year 0079
of the Universal Century.
The "second moon” known as Luna II
was an asteroid that was brought
to provide the mineral resources
needed to build the space colonies.
Next to it is the seventh city,
Side 7, whose construction began two years before war broke out between,
the Principality of Zeon
and the Earth Federation.
Four clusters of colonies
have been destroyed in this war,
and now only a few of
the Side 6 colonies remain.
The colony cluster called
the Principality of Zeon is located...
...the farthest away from Earth.
Its supreme commander,
Gihren Zabi, cried out,
"Strike the weakness of
the Earth Federation!”
It was as if he were the only one
who could ever save humanity.
Cucuruz Doan's Island
Core Fighter, Amuro. Can you hear us?
The Gunperry has been launched.
Roger. I'll make contact
We'll start counting once you initiate docking.
We want to reduce the time
by 3 seconds.
Roger that. Mr. Ryu, are you ready?
You bet!
Amuro, standby for docking.
I can do it.
Mr. Ryu, synchronize docking searcher.
Laser searcher synchronized.
5.. 4.. 3..
2... 1...
Gundam B Parts released!
Core Change! Docking, go!
Exactly 19 seconds.
Too slow. Can you cut 4 more?
That sounds impossible.
It's taking the laser searcher
time to synchronize.
Mr. Bright, a mayday signal
from the Federation air force.
The Federation air force?
Where is it? The enemy's numbers?
Well, it's an automated signal,
So we can't communicate.
I'll look into it.
Point 305.
Point 305, huh...
That's not too far.
I'll have Amuro check it out.
Amuro, separate Core Fighter
from Gundam.
Go check out Point 305
in the Core Fighter.
Roger.
Mr. Ryu, I'm releasing the Gundam parts.
Will you retrieve them?
Of course.
Though, I don't like seeing it
Oh yeah?
Mr. Bright. Here I go!
Oh, darn it.
I hate to see the Gundam like this.
Point 305... That must be it.
Is that it?
They're still alive?
Right.
Try to get information from them.
Amuro, tell me if you need anything.
Tsk, the Federation isn't even
coming for them?
The enemy
may still be lurking somewhere.
Call for level 2 battle stations.
Yes, sir.
Oh, no...
Stay still.
But why did they leave these pilots in the seats and just take their weapons without finishing them off?
Who's there?
Are you okay?
Go away, you soldier!
Yeah, go on home!
Stop it, kids!
I'm not your enemy.
Whatever! Leave!
Yeah, leave this island, now!
I said, stop it!
Shut up!
Take this!
Let's destroy that fighter plane too.
Hold it right there.
Darn it...
It's Doan! Yay!
- Doan!
I-I didn't think this island was occupied by Zeon.
I don't get it...
Hey Doan, we've got another soldier
on our island.
He pointed a gun at us!
We're not looking for a fight
Surrender your weapons,
and we won't harm you.
Surrender my weapons?
The ball is in your hands.
Why don't you just finish me off?
We don't want to fight,
so I'm asking you.
Kids, stay here where it's safe.
Doan, just crush him!
Yeah, do it!
You think you can beat
this Zaku with a plane like that?
I may not be able to finish it off,
but I can immobilize it
with a precision missile attack.
If I can destroy the joints...
So fast!
Again!
Ow...
You are...?
Rollan.
Where on earth am I?
The home of Doan and the kids.
Doan?
Cucuruz Doan.
He's the one who saved you.
What did you say?
Don't worry, Doan will let you go.
Rest here until you feel better.
I don't believe you.
Besides, where did you take
my Core Fighter?
It's just like Doan said.
Doan's in the field with the kids.
Look, it's him!
Young man.
It seems like you've recovered.
Where is it?!
Your fighter plane?
I must put the safety of these kids first.
The Zeon guys will find me here
sooner or later and attack me.
It's the same for me.
I need my weapons to protect myself.
Give me back my Core Fighter!
But if I do that,
you'll come after me, too. Right?
I'm not a coward like you,
who tricks kids for your schemes.
I'm fighting the Zeon invaders.
Don't talk like that about Doan!
Doan's not tricking us!
Yeah, he's protecting our island!
Leave, if that's what you think.
Yeah, we don't want you here!
You've trained them well.
What did you say!? You...
Stop it.
Fighting brings nothing good.
I always tell you that.
But, this guy...
I'll find the Core Fighter,
one way or another.
Mobile Suit
Gundam
He couldn't have taken it that far.
Doan, he won't find it, will he?
Yeah, he'll never find it!
Yeah never.
You're more stubborn than I thought.
Spying on me?
You don't even see the beauty
in that sunset, do you?
Beauty is useless in war.
It's a dangerous distraction.
Doan isn't the man you think he is.
He seems to be good at
deceiving children, doesn't he?
You don't know anything.
Who are you to say that?
If he's so great,
why would he hide my Core Fighter?
You don't know what those kids
have been going through.
They're not so naive
that they'd blindly follow Doan here.
Then, why does he take care of them?
Ask him yourself,
if you want to know.
Doan sees something in you.
He says that
if you grow up a bit more,
then you'll be a great soldier.
I don't see anyone down here.
Ryu, we're ending
our search mission for today.
But...
Can't he see
that we're really worried?
He should contact us.
It's Amuro we're talking about.
I'm sure he has his reasons.
I hope so...
I hope he's not...
I'm so stupid.
-A-A Zaku's here!
So, Zeon's nowhere to be seen?
You're still up?
What are you going to do?
What, about that boy?
Well, we can't just leave him be.
I'm sure his main force
is somewhere nearby.
Unless he changes his mind,
he'll be trouble.
I've lived in fear for too long.
I'd like to free myself soon.
I'm so sorry...
Don't worry about me.
There he is!
Get off this island, now!
Yeah!
There!
Stop it!
So you didn't get
much sleep either, huh?
I'll resume the search!
An unidentified object, approaching.
It's coming fast.
Is it coming this way?
No, it's heading towards Point 305.
Let's send Ryu there.
Okay. The White Base will go, too.
Yes, sir.
Leave, now!
Get off this island, now!
Go away!
It's a Zaku!
Run!
Hurry!
Where are the kids!?
Um...
Doan!
Doan I need my Core Fighter.
Watch out!
The house...
Doan!
Follow me.
That Zaku... What's it after?
So fast.
Amuro, you're alive!
Mr. Ryu!
What's going on?
I explain later,
One of the Zakus is on our side.
Here it comes.
It's the White Base.
Amuro, are you okay?
Yes! Please launch the Gundam at once.
I'll dock in mid-air.
No, land on the ship and then convert.
Omur, prepare for conversion!
But my skills have improved...
Here I go!
There's only one Zaku left
Hold it. I'll take on this one.
But you don't have enough weapons.
I'll show you what a melee combat between
mobile suits looks like. Watch closely.
But... Doan!
Stop it!
But...
As long as the kids are watching,
I'll keep on fighting.
- Doan, beat up that Zaku!
Yeah, you'll win!
Go get him!
Amuro, what's happening?
I don't really get it either...
I'll tell you, boys!
The one who killed
the kids' parents is...
me!
They were killed by
a stray bullet I shot.
Zeon told me to kill the kids, too.
But I couldn't do it.
So I ran, taking the kids with me.
I protect these kids,
even it it costs me my life!
Doan!
I...
The kids...
I won't let you kill them!
Doan, you were awesome!
You're our hero!
Those guys will come after me,
as long as I'm alive.
If I stay with them, the kids
will continue to be in danger.
What am I to do...
No, it's not because you're with them.
It's the stench of war on you
that attracts the pursuers.
Stench of war?
Yeah,
let me remove it.
Cucuruz Doan.
Hey!
You're hurting it!
Stop it!
Doan...
- We'll get him.
Kids, stop it.
Don't get angry at the boy.
Why, oh why?
Look what he just did!
He did the right thing.
Rollan, he's a nice boy.
Don't you think?
Yes...
The Gallop and Gouf appear in the desert.
Sayla, wanting to know
Char's whereabouts,
takes off on her own,
violating orders.
However, her reckless maneuver
puts the Gundam in great danger...
Will Amuro fight to save her?
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Sayla's Agony.
Next Time
Sayla's Agony
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...